# Dr DE HERDT Véronique

# **Family Physician**



# **Professional Summary**

Passionate and committed Family physician with **11 years of experience in private practice.** Member of a medical team in a clinic of Family Physicians and GPs in Brussels, capital of Europe with a large **diversity of people** and culture and I have wide experiences in treating various diseases among women, men, children and elderly.

#### **PERSONALIA**

Family name: De Herdt First name: Véronique

Date/Place of birth: 10th January 1978 (39Y), Brussels (Belgium)

Nationality: Belgium Civil state: married

Address: Jalan Setia Perdana 45 U13/25A, Setia Alam, Shah Alam, Malaysia

E-mail: veronique.deherdt@gmail.com

Phone: +6012 205 73 10

#### **WORKING EXPERIENCE**

2016-2005: Family Physician, private practice in a clinic in Brussels, Belgium

Working as a Family Physician in an outpatient clinic (*Centre Medical Meris*) together with other GPs and Family Physicians to give primary care services for patients of all ages.

The medical team (four Family Physicians, two GPs, a Dentist, a Physiotherapist and a nurse) was handling more than 5000 patients and we provided:

- Emergency services for acute illness (infectious disease, abdominal pain, law back pain, acute chest pain etc and its investigations as labs and ECG with referrals at ED if needed) and injury
- Family and internal medicine for the screening, following, management of chronic illnesses as diabetes, chronic heart disease, chronic kidney disease, thyroid pathology and systemic disease, etc, in partnership with the specialist

- Minor surgery and dermatology (stitching open wounds, cryotherapy and curettage for warts, mollusca or benign dermatological lesions as actinic keratosis, investigations and management of eczema, hair loss,...)
- **O&G:** pregnancy follow up, contraception, STI management and treatment, cancer screening (pap smear, clinic breast examination and investigations)
- **Pediatrics:** growth following, child development milestones, acute infections (skin infections, URTI, LUTI,...), diagnosis, management and referrals for main common childhood complain as cough, abdominal pain (coeliac disease, CMPA,...), failure to thrive, lameness, common childhood infection (HFMD, varicella,...), emergencies (diagnosis and urgent referral for appendicitis, intussusception, suspicion of meningitis...)
- Prevention healthcare: screening, lab tests and specific appropriate investigations
  exam in function of the age, the gender and risk factor of the patient (pap smear, fecal
  occult blood testing, serum PSA and endorectal ultrasound, clinical breast examination
  and further investigations as ultrasonography or mammography if appropriated for cancer screening; cardiac risk factor assessment, electrocardiogram for hypertensive patients)
- **Pediatric and adult immunization** following the national schedule or individualized schema
- Workshops for the patients: nutrition workshop for the Moms, workshop about infectious diseases prevention (HIV, STI...) and contraception methods, first aid workshop (carbon monoxide intoxication, burns, electric shock, cardiopulmonary resuscitation)
- Counseling to enhance well-being: nutritional assessment and advices for children and pregnant women, weight loss and quit smoking (with therapeutic support if needed)

**Supervision of medical students** during housemanship for MD or Family Medicine specialization (Free University Brussels, Catholic University of Leuven). Major concern about the patient relationship, take history of the patient and underlying conditions and clinical examination. Discussion about the diagnosis and treatment.

**2005-2006**: ONE (*Offine National de l'Enfance*), working as a GP in a Belgian's national prevention center for babies and toddler:

- Childhood screening (head circumference, weight, length, child development milestones)
- Immunization (Belgian national schedule)
- Advise parents against cot death, nutrition and current childhood diseases

**2005-2003**: Housemanship for Family Physician under the supervision of Dr ABOUAYAD M., Family Physician. Subject of the final thesis « Fasting during Ramadan month and its consequences on diabetic patients ».

**2005-2016** Emergency medicine (« La garde Bruxelloise »). Call on service for Brussels area.

# **EDUCATION**

2017 : Basic Course on **Ultrasound** in Medical (Agensi Nuklear Malaysia); hands on ultrasound training for basic general and basic obstetrics scheduled on May and June 2017

2015: **Phythotherapy** cursus on CFNA (Phytotherapy and Nutritherapy formation center), Namur University, Belgium

2015: Certificate of competence in **Electrocardiography**, Free University of Brussels (Belgium)

2003-2005: Master, Specialization in Family Medicine

1999-2003: MD medicine, Free University of Brussels (Belgium)

1996-1999: **BsC Medicine**, Free University of Brussels (Belgium)

#### **THESIS**

2005: Master's thesis (specialization Family medicine) « Fasting during Ramadan month and its consequences on diabetic patients », Free University Brussels

2003: Final thesis (Medical degree) « Tuberculosis of CNS », Free University Brussels

#### **LANGUAGES**

English: good

French: native speaker

Dutch: basic

Arabic: notions

# **AFFILIATION:**

2003-2016 : Belgian Medical Board (Ordre des médecins) for APC

2007-2016: INAMI accreditation (National Institute of disease and disability) annual governmental licence that ensure the Family Physician handle a minimum of patients and attends a minimum of updating courses (CME); www.inami.fgov.be

SSMG: member of scientific society of Family Medicine of Belgium from 2011

# **TRAINING**

2017: Basic Course on **Ultrasound** in Medical (Agensi Nuklear Malaysia); hands on ultrasound training for basic general and basic obstetrics scheduled on May and June 2017.

11-2016: Klang Valley **Infectious diseases** updating: Endocarditis, Leptospirosis, Meloidosis, Typhoid, Malaria.

01-2016: SSMG (Scientific Society of Family Physician); Diagnoses and Drugs updating: New treatments in rheumatology, New treatments in osteoarthrosis of the knee, New treatments in gastroenterology.

09-2015: Annual congress of AMUB (Free University Brussels Medical Association): Prenatal Down's syndrome screening, Newborn screening, Systematic follow-up of infants born preterm, Treatment of main chronic diseases in childhood from birth, Practical approach of lymphomas, Breast cancer screening, Melanoma secondary prevention, Preventing cervical cancer, Colorectal cancer, Skin sampling for the GP, Intra-articular injections, Management of chronic wounds, The secondary prevention of of osteoporosis, Therapeutic algorithm of LBP, Rehabilitation after total arthroplasty of hip and knee

02-2015: SSMG (Scientific Society of Family Physician); Pediatric Day: ADHD, Static disorder in childhood, Vaccination, Fall in children, Food intolerance, Dermatology in children.

09-2014: Annual congress of AMUB (Free University Brussels Medical Association): Anti-pneumococcal vaccination, Recent epidemiology of pertussis, Is it necessary to vaccinate against varicella, HPV vaccines, New oral anti diabetic drugs, Management of cardiovascular risk in the elderly patient, Anaemia in older persons, Specificities of pneumonia in geriatrics, Euthanasia, Dementia.

02-2014: SSMG (Scientific Society of Family Physician); Neurology Day: Headache, Loss of consciousness, Images of the brain, Drugs updating.

09-2013: Annual congress of AMUB (Free University Brussels Medical Association): Inappropriate prescribing in the eldery, Tuberculosis screening, Biomarkers of Alzheimer's disease, Screening for prostate cancer by PSA, Refractory anemias, Pitfalls of monoclonal gammopathy, Rational approach of leucocytosis in adults, Iron's up and dawns, The alarming increase of incapacity for work, Physical restraint and procedure, The setting in observation and involuntary treatments.

02-2012: SSMG (Scientific Society of Family Physician); Urology Day: Urinary incontinence, dipstick, labs and CKD, PSA, UTI, STI, EPO treatment in CKD, Kidney's stones.

01-2012: SSMG (Scientific Society of Family Physician); Diagnoses and Drugs updating: Management and treatment in menopause, updating in vaccination pneumonia, meningitis and varicella, new anticoagulants treatment in AF.

02-2011: SSMG (Scientific Society of Family Physician); Diabetes Day: Diabetes in eldery, Diabetes and CVR, New treatments in T2M, Insuline treatment.

01-2011: SSMG (Scientific Society of Family Physician); Allergy: Anaphylactic shock, Cross allergies, Newborn allergies, diagnosis of professional allergies.

# **HOBBIES**:

- Volunteering activities:
  - Belgium member of the board of directors of « ATMB » (Belgian Islamic Medical Association) working for relief of refugees and disadvantaged people and workshop about ethic problems encountered in medical practice.
  - Malaysia, working with IMARET in charity clinics for Refugees and poor people.
- Diving, horse riding, roller skating
- Reading, cooking.